<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SpaCy on Ydn&#39;s personal blog.</title>
    <link>https://yudanta.github.io/tags/spacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SpaCy on Ydn&#39;s personal blog.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 19:25:46 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yudanta.github.io/tags/spacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Spacy Ner With Fast Api</title>
      <link>https://yudanta.github.io/posts/deploy-spacy-ner-with-fast-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 19:25:46 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yudanta.github.io/posts/deploy-spacy-ner-with-fast-api/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post here: https://yudanta.github.io/posts/train-an-indonesian-ner-from-a-blank-spacy-model/, I shared about how to train simple Indonesian NER model with SpaCy. The detail of training process can be found in that article. In this post, we will focus on how to deploy the model as a REST API with FastAPI, so the users can query to our NER model via REST API. However, in this tutorial, will focus on how to create simple FastAPI project and load pre-trained NER model, if you are not familiar with FastAPI yet, please go to the FastAPI documentation site here: https://fastapi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train an Indonesian NER From a Blank SpaCy Model</title>
      <link>https://yudanta.github.io/posts/train-an-indonesian-ner-from-a-blank-spacy-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 23:23:57 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yudanta.github.io/posts/train-an-indonesian-ner-from-a-blank-spacy-model/</guid>
      <description>So, how we train a Named Entity Recognition model in SpaCy using our own dataset? long story short, though the title is in English, but this time I will write the story in Indonesian, since the model is an Indonesian Named Entity Recognition.
Jadi&amp;hellip; bagi yang ingin bikin model untuk keperluan &amp;ldquo;sequence-tagging&amp;rdquo; seperti Ekstraksi Entitas dan Pengenalan Entitas, maka biar tidak pusing atau pusing dengan bikin model pakai stack LSTM atau LSTM+CRF seperti kebanyakan yang ada di tutorial-tutorial itu, apalagi pakai embedding kaya word2vec dan glove dan bert fang femes itu kan overkill&amp;hellip; dan tentunya bakal lama, ya to ya?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
